<ArrayOfThemeData xmlns:i="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://schemas.datacontract.org/2004/07/WSU.Locations.DTO"><ThemeData><Description>Learn about various trees found on Winona State's campus.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>1</ThemeId><ThemeName>Tree Tour</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>A legume is a plant in the family Fabaceae, or the fruit or seed of such a plant. Legumes are grown agriculturally, primarily for their food grain seed, for livestock forage and silage, and as soil-enhancing green manure. These plants are beneficial to native plant gardens because they help enhance the nitrogen fixation in soils by soil rhizobium (beneficial bacteria).</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>3</ThemeId><ThemeName>Legume Family</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>Grasses, or more technically graminoids, are monocotyledonous, usually herbaceous plants with narrow  lance shaped leaves growing from the base.  They have round hollow stems and branching roots. They are staples of the prairie ecosystem.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>4</ThemeId><ThemeName>Grass Family</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>Examples of plants that are fit to be eaten.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>5</ThemeId><ThemeName>Edible</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>Plants capable of or having properties that can be used to treat illness.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>6</ThemeId><ThemeName>Medicinal</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>Specific trees of Winona State University highlighted during the annual Shakespeare Festival in July.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>18</ThemeId><ThemeName>Shakespeare Tree Tour</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>Plants in this section have characteristics that provide nectar to attract bulltterflies.  They may also attract pollinators like bees, flies, and other insects.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>19</ThemeId><ThemeName>Butterflies</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>Plants in this section are those that have the type of blossom or seed that attracts birds; such as bergamot, columbine and beardtongue attracting hummingbirds and coneflower attracting finches.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>20</ThemeId><ThemeName>Birds</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>In the Landscape Arboretum at Winona State University, we’re concerned about pollinators and wildlife.  Here are some of the flowering and fruiting trees in our collection.  The trees can be seen flowering at various times in the spring and fruiting in the summer and fall.  There is also winter interest with persistent fruit on some of the trees.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>24</ThemeId><ThemeName>Flowering Trees of WSU</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>This garden intends to highlight the distinction between native plants and the more widely available “cultivars” found in commercial garden centers. The majority of plants in this garden are cultivars, many being derived from native Minnesota species.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>26</ThemeId><ThemeName>Cultivar Garden</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>This bioswale, located on the southeast corner of the IWC, was created as part of the Integrated Wellness Complex construction completed in 2011. It captures stormwater runoff from the adjacent roof and supports the LEED Certification of the IWC building. The plants listed here were observed on-site July 2021.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>27</ThemeId><ThemeName>Bioswale #3</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>These two bioswales along Johnson Street were created as part of the Integrated Wellness Complex construction completed in 2011.  They capture stormwater runoff from the adjacent roof and support the LEED Certification of the IWC building. This plant inventory was observed on-site July 2021.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>28</ThemeId><ThemeName>Bioswale #1 &amp; #2</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>This bioswale was created as part of the construction of Education Village completed in 2019.  It captures stormwater runoff from the adjacent 10,000 square foot parking lot.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>29</ThemeId><ThemeName>Bioswale #4</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>This bioswale was created as part of the construction of Education Village completed in 2019. It captures stormwater runoff from the adjacent 7,800 square foot parking lot.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>30</ThemeId><ThemeName>Bioswale #5</ThemeName></ThemeData><ThemeData><Description>The plantbeds around the Younger Courtyard (aka the Clock Tower Courtyard) were renovated summer 2021. The new planting design was selected to provide habitat specifically for the Rusty Patched Bumble Bee (Bombus affinis), Minnesota’s state bee.</Description><ThemeColor i:nil="true" /><ThemeId>34</ThemeId><ThemeName>Younger Courtyard</ThemeName></ThemeData></ArrayOfThemeData>